He was their inspiration. He made their lives extraordinary.
Dead Poets Society is a drama film directed by Peter Weir.
At an elite, old-fashioned boarding school in New England, a passionate English teacher inspires his students to rebel
against convention and seize the potential of every day, courting the disdain of the stern headmaster.
John Keating, played by Robin Williams.
Neil Perry, played by Robert Sean Leonard.
Todd Anderson, played by Ethan Hawke.
Knox Overstreet, played by Josh Charles.
Charlie Dalton, played by Gale Hansen.
Richard Cameron, played by Dylan Kussman.
Dead Poets Society is a 1989 American coming-of-age drama film
directed by Peter Weir and written by Tom Schulman.
The film, starring Robin Williams, is set in 1959 at a
fictional elite boarding school called Welton Academy.
It tells the story of an English teacher who inspires his
students through his teaching of poetry.
Dead Poets Society was produced by Touchstone Pictures and Silver Screen Partners IV and
released in the United States by Buena Vista Pictures Distribution on June 2, 1989.
The film was a commercial success and received critical acclaim.
It grossed $235.9 million worldwide against a $16.4 million budget,
becoming the fifth-highest-grossing film of 1989.
The film received numerous accolades, including Academy Award nominations for Best
Picture and Best Director and a Best Actor nomination for Williams.
The film won the BAFTA Award for Best Film, the César Award for Best Foreign
Film and the David di Donatello Award for Best Foreign Film.
Schulman received the Academy Award for Best Original Screenplay for his work.
The film explores themes of individual,
friendship, philosophy, poetry, literature.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional and intense.